nwpresident.com 2015-03-15

# Privacy

### Privacy

NWP Services Corporation is committed to preserving the privacy and security of the personal information and data collected on our website [www.nwpsc.com](http://www.nwpsc.com/).

This privacy policy is designed to inform you about the types of information we gather about you and your organization, how we may use that information, whether we disclose it to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of that information. This policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically.

In addition to our privacy policy, we also recommend you read our terms and conditions for important information regarding your rights and obligations, as well as limitations and exclusions, that apply to your use of the site.

**What information do we collect from you?**  
Our site collects two types of information about its visitors: personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information. Our primary goal in collecting information is to provide you with efficient and effective service while using our site.

Personally identifiable information: This refers to information that specifically identifies who you are. We request personally identifiable information when you set up an account, contact our customer service, fill out surveys or correspond with us. This information might include your name, mailing address, telephone number and/or email address.

Non-personally identifiable information: This refers to information that does not by itself identify a specific individual. We gather this information each time you access our site. This information, compiled and analyzed on both a personal and an aggregated basis, may include the Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") of the website you visited just prior to accessing our site, the URL you go to after leaving our site, what browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address. A URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol ("TCP/IP") network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web, allowing Web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet and browse.

**How do we use the information that we receive from you?**  
Our primary goal in collecting personal information from our customers and other visitors to our site is to provide those customers and visitors with a superior customized online and general customer care experience. We use customer contact information to provide faster, more effective service in connection with your billing questions, to contact you regarding the status of your account, to track your billing and payment activity on your account, and to send promotional emails about products and services that may be of interest to them.

We may also perform statistical analysis of aggregate customer behavior. For instance, we may analyze which pages on our site receive the most visitors or how long visitors spend reviewing those pages when visiting the site. This allows us to measure relative customer interest in the various areas of our site. We then use that information to improve the content of our site, to enhance your experience when visiting the site, to customize the content and/or layout of the site’s pages and to provide the services required by our individual customers.

**With whom do we share your information?**  
The information collected by the site is used only for the limited purposes of sending your utility bill, processing your payments, contacting you regarding account status, keeping you informed about your account, for statistical purposes for improving the site and to notify you of items that may be of interest to you. We will disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties to send you a utility bill, charge your credit card, process another form of payment transaction, provide customer service to you, contact you regarding the status of your account, and deliver promotional emails to you from us. For example, we must release your credit card number to confirm payment and release your mailing address information to our bill print vendor to send you a utility bill. These third parties have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

We do not sell, trade or rent your personal information to others. We may release account information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to enforce or apply our terms and conditions or to protect the rights, property and safety of our users, others and ourselves.

Except as otherwise stated in this policy, at present we do not disclose our customers' personally identifiable information to other merchants. In the future, with your prior permission, we may provide some customer information to companies with products or services that may be of interest to you. This would be for marketing purposes only and no credit card number information would be given. Before agreeing to release your information, you should first confirm that our partner's privacy policy is acceptable to you because once your data is released, we would have no further control over it.

From time to time, we may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will disclose personally identifiable information upon receipt of a court order or subpoena or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation. We fully cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. As expressed in the terms and conditions that govern this site, we reserve the right to conduct an investigation and/or report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful.

We may assign or otherwise transfer to a third party certain of your information in connection with an assignment, sale, transfer or disposition of a portion or all of our business, assets, or stock.

**Opting out**  
We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference when setting up your online account with us.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [privacy@nwpsc.com](mailto:privacy@nwpsc.com) or you may contact us at 800-845-6767 to opt out. You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

**Security**  
The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100 percent secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at [privacy@nwpsc.com](mailto:privacy@nwpsc.com) or call us by phone toll free at 800-845-6767.

**Privacy Policy changes.**  
We may change, modify, add or remove portions of this privacy policy at any time. Please be sure to check this page before proceeding to use our site.
